Why are you tapping on it?
Doing this tells me where the wood is rotten or eaten by bugs. / Bugs?
Wood-eating bugs.
Oops, found one. Look here. / Ugh, gross!
All right, then let's burn this piece.
What happens if we just leave it?
When heavy rain fills the pond, the sluice gate will break.
Hmm, why would it break?
From the water pressure.
Pressure is incredible. But just one tiny hole should be fine, right?
No, no. As the saying goes, even a massive levee can collapse from a single ant hole.
What does that mean?
It means even a sturdy dike can be destroyed starting from one little ant hole.
(Always be careful, even with little things.)
That's terrible. Then everything would be flooded!
Indeed. And that's not all.
If the reservoir empties, crops won't grow, and we won't have drinking water either.
Oh no, that's awful! I'll help you too.
Here.
Thank you.
Thank you. You're such a kind boy.
Why are you calling Mokku?
You don't get it? We're gonna use him.
Use him how?
The water's still cold, right?
So we put Mokku in the water to flush out the fish.
Oh, I see. Good idea.
We're catching fish! It's fun! Come over here!
Fish? What should I do?
I'm going!
Hey, Mokku!
Wait!
Hopeless boy. He's only interested in playing.
(Fast-forwarding)
Aaargh! I can't take it anymore! Hey, that's carp! The smell is incredible... look how plump it is!
You're right! Carp sashimi is quite the luxury, hey!
Whoa, well said! As expected of you, with your good upbringing, you really know your food! Carp sashimi is irresistible, isn't it?
Idiot! I'm starving! That lunch of yours didn't fill me up at all! Look at this!
Huh? I'm sorry, boss.
All right, go swipe that carp!
W-What? No, I can't! At night maybe, but in broad daylight...
You slow-witted fool. You've got a weasel's last trick—a real good stinker—don't you?
But, Bro, that's what you use when you're running away. I wonder why.
What do you mean "why"?! You distract them with a stink powerful enough to rip their nose off, and that's your chance!
Hey, brilliant!
Ready?
Standing by!
Ready to go?
Gotta do it! Gotta do it! Gotta do it!
He did it!
(Sound of wind)
Urrghhh!
Gwah! (Sound of wind)
So fast!
Bro, it's the wind's fault! It's the wind!
I wonder why.
Ha... ha... *splash splash splash*... Ha, I'm... I'm...
(Sound of wind)
Haah...
Ah!
It came off!
It reached him!
What's this? A woodworm?
Huh? It looks just like the bugs at the sluice gate!
I see, it washed down here.
Unbelievable, trying to eat my foot.
To guide my mother who held the belongings, I had nothing that brought me so close to the coward's basic nature of the protagonist.
However, I had nothing at hand that came so close to the essence of a cowardly protagonist.
In the rumors, the same cowardly nature was depicted.
My butt...
It's broken! It's broken!
Let's go! Let's go! Let's go home!
Damn that Franco!
Grandpa will make me a new one!
(children's voices)
(Father) All done. Here is your new leg. (children's voices)
(Father) It's the exact same size as the old one.
(Father) Here, let me attach it for you. (children's voices)
No one will laugh at you now. Try walking. / Thank you, Grandpa.
What is the matter?
I tripped.
My leg won't move.
Mokku!
Grandpa, why did you make me a leg like this?!
I want a leg that moves like before!
B-But even if you say that...
Grandpa has no idea why it won't move either...
(sobbing)
(Man) Puppet! Keep walking and crying!
(Woman) How nice...
When everyone else plays in the river, they don't get woodworms...
Even if they get muddy, they're fine once they wash off!
And yet, I'm... (sobbing)
I hate this... I hate it! I don't want to be a puppet anymore!
(sobbing)
M-Mokku... (sobbing)
Aaahhh!
Don't you get it? No matter how much it's made from an Oak Tree, it won't move.
Not without the Oak Tree Fairy's power.
Aaah... I'm so hungry! I've got to eat somehow! I want to eat this!
Wait! I've got a great idea!
Jackpot! Time to eat!
Huh? A master who can make legs that move?
Shh! Keep your voice down!
That's right! There's a master leg-maker around!
W-Where is this master?
You want us to tell you?
Please!
I could tell you, but not for free!
Yeah!
What do you mean? What should I do?
Oh, nothing much. Just lend us a hand for a bit. Simple as that.
Even this is better than not being able to move.
Mokku, what are you doing?
I'm leaving.
Leaving? Where to?
Leave me alone. What does it matter where?
Fine. If you want to know that badly, I'll tell you.
I'm going to a master puppet maker who's way, way better than Grandpa, to have him make me a persimmon!
Much better?
That's right.
There's no master like that.
Yes, there is!
Nobody anywhere can make a puppet that moves like a real human.
Yes, there is! I heard all about him!
No, there isn't.
Goodbye. Good night!
Mokku!
Hmm, having legs that won't move must be tough.
Come on, tell me. What do you want me to do?
It's simple, really. Just catch two or three fish from this reservoir for me.
Catch them? How, without any tools?
It's a piece of cake. Look, we just open this floodgate and drain the water. Then you can just grab 'em with your bare hands without any gear.
All right, I'll try. But in return, once you catch the fish, you have to...
Yeah, I'll push you!
Good boy, good boy. We don't have to lift a finger and we can eat all we want, that's how it is.
As expected of you, Brother, your mind is so sharp. I wonder why that is.
(Sound of running water)
Hey, Mokku!
If you do that, the water will rush out and the whole town will be in big trouble!
What, you again?!
Stop it, Mokku! Are you trying to flood the whole town?!
Shut up! I want legs! Legs that move!
(Sound of water splashing)
Hey, hurry it up!
If the handle won't work, why not try smashing it with a rock?
I'm starving... I want food...
Here?
Brother, it's raining.
Shall we go?
Where are you going?
To take shelter from the rain. I hate getting wet.
Please tell me if you're leaving.
You bastard! Are you trying not to let me eat?!
That Kenken... next time I see him, he won't get off easy!
The ants have it nice. Under the big tree, not having to worry about the rain.
Please rest a little...
There's so much water...
That's where I slammed into it...
It won't stop...
As they say, even a massive dike can collapse from a single ant hole.
Even a sturdy dike can be destroyed by one tiny ant hole!
Grandpa!
What are you dawdling for?! Hurry up and plug the leak!
H-How?
Stuff it with wood!
Wood? There isn't any wood around here!
Yes there is! You're made of wood!
M-Me? You're telling me to use my own body to stop the water?
There's no other way!
No! I don't want to!
There!
What are you messing around for?! Hurry, or the floodgate will break!
No way! If I lose these arms and legs, there are no replacements!
Fine! Then let the whole town drown in water!
Grandpa will just drown and die, too!
Thank goodness, it held.
Hm?
Mokku!
Mokku...
Mokku, you...
You drove your own body into it for me...?
Well, Grandpa.
I'm going to go deliver the order.
You are...
Mokku, I saw everything. Your noble deed. You did well to save the townspeople.
You were magnificent. Truly magnificent. I have come to give you life once again. [Music]
I can move!
Please, wait! How was I restored?
You sacrificed your precious limbs to save others. Compassion for people...
...that is the heart known as love. Your love...
...has given you life. / My love did?
Come on! Hey, this is dangerous!
Whaaat?! A fork?!
Look out if you're not paying attention! We're in the middle of a match! Hey, Mokku!
Hurry!
Wait!
Get 'em!
Nice going, Mokku!
Mokku becomes friends with Chikaro, a monkey who can speak just like a human.
Learning that Chikaro lives in a wealthy mansion, Kenken and the others threaten Mokku to make him bring them food.
However, when Mokku is caught stealing the food, he ends up chained up along with Chikaro, who is about to be sold to a circus.
Don't miss next week's Kashi no Ki Mokku!